# **Lloyd Chambrier**

110 Green Street – Brooklyn, NY 11222 Phone: 917.246.2250 – Email: lloydchambrier@gmail.com

#### **SKILLS**

- Web Development Framework: Rails and AngularJS.
- **Programming Languages**: Proficient at using HTML, CSS and Ruby. Able to use C, C++, Java and JavaScript.
- **IDE**: Sublime Text.
- **Software:** Microsoft Word, Excel, PowerPoint and Access;
- International Travel: Gabon, France, England, Argentina, Morocco and India.
- Languages: Fluent in both French and English. Moderate in Spanish.

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### **Admissions Counselor**

**December 2014 – Present** 

The New York Code + Design Academy

I worked part-time for one of the top coding schools in Manhattan.

As Admissions Counselor, I had to:

- Conduct and engage outbound/inbound calls and emails to prospective students.
- Schedule tours and interviews.
- Educate prospective students on current courses offerings.
- Professionally assist prospective students and families through the admissions process.
- Maintain prospective student records using SugarCRM.
- Organize Open House events + Prospective Employers Fair

#### **Teaching Assistant**

**January 2015 – May 2015** 

The New York Code + Design Academy

I worked part-time

## IT Support Technician

**January 2013 – June 2013** 

Olam International. India

I did a six-month internship in a leading agri-business company in Chennai.

As an IT technician, I had to:

- Generate login credentials for consultants from outside the company to have access to the company' system.
- Set up VPN conference calls for the company's executives/staff.
- Solve computer-related issues for staff members.

• Generated weekly reports to be filed in the company' system.

### **Assistant Web Developer**

**June 2011 – August 2011** 

Gabonews, Gabon

I took an internship in a local news agency in Libreville.

As an assistant web developer, I had to:

- Keep track of our users' requests and forward them to the development team.
- Help the development team in building a better interface for the company' website.
- Maintain and update articles online.

#### **Sales Assistant**

January 2005 – December 2010

Ismad, UK

A designer accessory brand specialized in bringing handcrafted Moroccan leather bags and belts to London's fashion scene.

As a sales assistant, I had to:

- Advertise and sell products.
- Communicate with our Moroccan suppliers and manage orders.
- Keep an accurate record of stocks, monthly expenses and sold merchandise.

#### **EDUCATION**

New York Code and Design Academy, USA

**June 2014 – July 2015** 

 Courses completed: Web Development 100, Ruby on Rails 101, AngularJS 102 & UI/UX Design 101

#### **Bachelor of Science**

September 2007 – September 2012

Oxford Brookes University, UK

- Majors: Computer Science & Software Engineering Joint Degree.
- Second Class 2:2 Mark (3.65 GPA USA Equivalent)

#### French Baccalaureate (Secondary School)

**September 2006 – June 2007** 

Lycee Français Blaise Pascal, Gabon

- French Baccalaureate (Scientific Orientation)
- TOEFL Certificate (Written and Spoken English).

#### **ABOUT ME**

After studying in England and moving abroad to experience the world outside my comfort zone, I've moved to New York because I want to thrive in this city and become a full-stack web developer. I'm an International student with a mind opened to everything from programming to technology and I enjoy creating websites and web applications as much as finding solutions to problems.

# REFERENCES

Upon Request